# PropTech Insights

> PropTech Insights is a PropTech consulting firm founded by Michael Marciano, helping companies shaping the future of real estate move faster with clarity. We work with PropTech startups, agencies, brokerages, lenders, platforms, and data companies — anyone building, scaling, or transforming something in the built environment. Services span technology strategy, product leadership, workflow automation, data systems, and digital transformation.

## About
- Founded by Michael Marciano, a PropTech strategist with 15+ years at the intersection of real estate and technology
- Previously held a senior product role at EG (Estates Gazette), part of the CoStar Group
- Host of the Pixel Chasing podcast covering PropTech and real estate technology
- Based in the United Kingdom, working with companies globally
- Tagline: "Native to Real Estate // Fluent in Tech"

## Services
- **Product Strategy & Leadership**: Comprehensive technology audits and strategic roadmaps. Assessing current systems, identifying gaps, and creating prioritised plans that align technology investments with growth objectives
- **Process & Workflow Design**: End-to-end digital transformation and process redesign. Modernising legacy processes, migrating manual workflows to digital systems, and improving client experience
- **Data & Decision Systems**: Property data strategy, reporting frameworks, analytics dashboards, and data-driven decision-making processes for clear visibility into performance and efficiency
- **Go-to-Market & Partnerships**: Market entry strategy and partnership development. Helping PropTech companies launch products, enter new markets, and build partnership ecosystems
- **Team Structuring & Enablement**: Organisational design, hiring strategies, and enablement programmes that accelerate team performance
- **Strategic Advisory**: Independent expert guidance on technology strategy, vendor evaluation, and digital transformation for the built environment

## Process
Our engagement follows four phases: Discovery (stakeholder interviews, process mapping, technology audits), Strategy (prioritised roadmap aligned with commercial goals), Implementation (executing alongside your team), and Optimisation (measuring results, iterating for continuous improvement).

## Expertise Areas
- PropTech strategy and consulting
- Real estate data and analytics
- Workflow automation for property firms
- Product management for built environment technology
- Digital transformation for real estate businesses
- Technology selection and vendor evaluation
- Go-to-market strategy for PropTech companies
- Team structuring and organisational design
- Agency licensing and data acquisition
- NPS improvement and customer experience in property tech

## Contact
- Website: https://www.proptechinsights.com
- Email: Michael@PropTechInsights.com
- LinkedIn: https://uk.linkedin.com/company/proptechinsights

## Blog — Latest Insights
- [What Is PropTech Consulting and Why Does It Matter?](https://www.proptechinsights.com/blog/what-is-proptech-consulting.html) — Explains what PropTech consulting involves, the difference between a consultant and a vendor, and when to hire one
- [How to Choose the Right PropTech Stack for Your Business](https://www.proptechinsights.com/blog/choosing-proptech-stack.html) — A practical framework for evaluating CRM, sourcing tools, compliance platforms, and other PropTech solutions
- [Workflow Automation in Real Estate: Where to Start](https://www.proptechinsights.com/blog/workflow-automation-real-estate.html) — How to identify automation opportunities in document collection, compliance, client comms, and pipeline management
- [Building a Data Strategy for Real Estate Companies](https://www.proptechinsights.com/blog/data-strategy-real-estate.html) — A guide to turning operational property data into competitive advantage through reporting, analytics, and spatial insight
- [AI in Real Estate: A Practical Guide for Decision Makers](https://www.proptechinsights.com/blog/ai-real-estate-practical-guide.html) — Where AI genuinely creates value in real estate, where it's overhyped, and how to evaluate AI tools

## Links
- [Website](https://www.proptechinsights.com)
- [Blog](https://www.proptechinsights.com/blog/)
- [LinkedIn](https://uk.linkedin.com/company/proptechinsights)
